Partial Inventory of the Alexander and Ethel Pronin collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Alexander and Ethel Pronin collection
1908-1991
91052
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 1 portfolio, 389 motion picture film reels (87.2 linear feet)
Writings, notes, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, video tapes, motion picture film, and miscellany relating to aspects of Russian and Soviet culture and history. Video use copies of some motion picture films available.
Pronin, Alexander
Pronin, Ethel
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, notes, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, video tapes, motion picture film, and miscellany relating to aspects of Russian and Soviet culture and history. Video use copies of some motion picture films available.
Soviet Union--History.; Soviet Union--Pictorial works.; Soviet Union--Civilization.; Russia--History.; Russia--Civilization.; Russia--Pictorial works.; Motion pictures.; Video tapes.; Audiotapes.
- Motion Picture Film Reels
  Scope and Contents note
  Partial list.
  - Around the Soviet Union: Battleship Aurora (Reel 1)
  - Soviet Science at Work (Reel 2)
  - Visit Estonia, Bukovina, Turkmenia, Tadzhikistan, Ukraine (Reel 3)
  - Health Necklace: The Green Patrol (Reel 4)
  - From Air to Ground: Parachute Training (Reel 5)
  - Army Parachute Training and Sports (Reel 6)
  - Kazakhstan Melodies (Reel 7)
  - Defying the Storms and the Wind (mountain climbing; women climbers) (Reel 8)
  - The Young Sportsmen Grew Up (sports for children) (Reel 9)
  - Around the Soviet Union: Duck Farm, Omsk (Reel 10)
  - We Are the Sixth (elections) (Reel 11)
  - Creative Jobs Await the Youth (Reel 12)
  - Power Industry: Solar Energy (Reel 13)
  - A Great Event: Forthcoming 26th Congress (Reel 14)
  - 25th CPSU Congress, Moscow (Reel 15)
  - Music in Their Lives (Reel 16)
  - Young Naturalists (Reel 17)
  - In Our Kindergarten (Reel 18)
  - As Long as You Are Alive (visiting a concentration camp) (Reel 19)
  - Soviet School and ARTEK (Reel 20)
  - Central documentary film studios, Moscow: Truth and Slander, 1975 (Reel 21)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 91052_f_0001518
    Label reads "Reel 21: Truth and Slander: Maoism (Soviet victory over Japan)." Narration in English. Duration 19:00. Black and white.
  - Our Gagarin (Reel 22)
  - Lunakhod No. 1: Vehicle on the Moon (Reel 23)
  - A Rude Awakening (emigration to Israel) (Reel 24)
  - The New Moscow Circus (Reel 25)
  - The Village of Bergiliskii (Reel 26)
  - Patterns of Ice (Reel 27)
  - Moscow, a City of Science (Reel 28)
  - This Is Caucasia (Reel 29)
  - The Soiuz and Apollo Linkup (Reel 30)
  - Health Comes First (Reel 31)
  - University Games (Reel 32)
  - Forum for European Communists (Reel 33)
  - Genetics (Reel 34)
  - Azerbaijan Arts (Reel 35)
  - Friendship Coast (Reel 36)
  - Stronger Soviet and Arab Friendship (Reel 37)
  - Soviet Georgia (Reel 38)
  - The Stronger Fair Sex (Reel 39)
  - The Working Class of the USSR (Reel 40)
  - Soviet Army Road to the Sky (Reel 41)
  - Subways in Five Soviet Cities (Reel 42)
  - Moscow Art Exhibit: India (Reel 43)
  - Armenia, My Native Land (Reel 44)
  - Red Square on May Day (Reel 45)
  - Military Engineers and Health Care (Reel 46)
  - The Soviet Army: Motorized Infantry (Reel 47)
  - State Dance of the Uzbekistan Republic (Reel 48)
  - Beyond the Sandhills (Reel 49)
  - Ukrainian Villages: New Look (Reel 50)
  - Land of Our Birth: Past and Present Jewish Life in the USSR: Part I (Reel 51)
  - Land of Our Birth: Past and Present Jewish Life in the USSR: Part II (Reel 52)
  - Soviet Trade Unions (Reel 53)
  - Brezhnev: Peaceful Deeds (Reel 54)
  - Soviet Gymnasts (Reel 55)
  - On Red Square (Reel 56)
  - Our Friends (Reel 57)
  - The Epic of Fergana Valley (Uzbekistan) (Reel 58)
  - A Village in the Center of Europe (Reel 59)
  - This Is Sport (Reel 60)
  - The Life of Muslims in the USSR (Reel 61)
  - Lenin: Seven Years in Switzerland (Reel 62)
  - Faster, Higher, Stronger (Olympic champions) (Reel 63)
  - From the Shore of the Baltic (Reel 64)
  - A Road Equal to Centuries (60th anniversary) (Reel 65)
  - Town on the Oka River (Serpukhov) (Reel 66)
  - A Year in a Ground Space Ship (Reel 67)
  - Preserve the Planet for Happiness (Reel 68)
  - How We Vacation (Reel 69)
  - The Spring of Victory (Reel 70)
  - The USSR: A Union Inviolable (Reel 71)
  - Rhythms and Tunes from Soviet Georgia (Reel 72)
  - Lenin's Childhood (Reel 73)
  - 12th World Festival of Youth (Reel 74)
  - New Ideas in Science and Technology (Reel 75)
  - Estonian SSR (Reel 76)
  - Soviet Rhythms and Soviet Sports (Reel 77)
  - 7th USSR Summer Games (Reel 78)
  - Meeting on the Volga (French-Soviet Friendship Society) (Reel 79)
  - School of Beauty Appreciation (Lithuania) (Reel 80)
  - The Children Come to the Circus (Reel 81)
  - Celebration on Victory Day (Reel 82)
  - Backyard Sportsmen (Reel 83)
  - 1975: International Women's Year: State Prize Winners (Reel 84)
  - Star Town: Space City (Reel 85)
  - We Studied in Moscow (Reel 86)
  - The Young Pioneers (Reel 87)
  - Nature and Your City (Reel 88)
  - Soviet Army Victorious at Stalingrad (Reel 89)
  - A Family of Scientists (Reel 90)
  - They Defended Their Motherland (Reel 91)
  - Life in the Georgian SSR (Reel 92)
  - New Achievements: 25th CPSU Congress (Reel 93)
  - Life and Work of the Painter Korens (Reel 94)
  - Children of the Planet (Reel 95)
  - Moscow University (Reel 96)
  - Middle School (Reel 97)
  - The World Beneath the Sun (Reel 98)
  - Kazakhstan (Reel 99)
  - Struggle for Peace (Reel 100)
  - Odessa, Hero City (Reel 101)
  - Girls of the Planet (Reel 102)
  - Teenage Sailors (Reel 103)
  - Ostankino District of Moscow: TV Tower (Reel 104)
  - Hello, Georgia (Reel 105)
  - Industry of the Soviet Union (Reel 106)
  - The Socialist Community (Reel 107)
  - Lithuanian SSR (Reel 108)
  - Dedicated to the 60th Anniversary (Reel 109)
  - Looking to the Next Century, 1986: (Reel 110)
  - An Epic's Beginning: Gagarin: Part I (Reel 111)
  - Komsomol: Young Communist League (Reel 112)
  - USSR Under Construction (Reel 113)
  - Moscow Music World (Reel 114)
  - Nine Days and All Her Life (Reel 115)
  - The Amber of Baltic Coast: Part I (Reel 116)
  - They Are Building Moscow (Reel 117)
  - Knowledge for the People (Reel 118)
  - Russian SFSR (Reel 119)
  - Heroes of Labor (Reel 120)
  - A Collective Farm in Kazakhstan (Reel 121)
  - We Are Working People (Reel 122)
  - Around the Soviet Union: Odessa (Reel 123)
  - State Farm "Zaria Komunizma" (Reel 124)
  - Right to Rest and Leisure (Reel 125)
  - Kirghiz SSR (Reel 126)
  - A Town on the Terek River (Ordzhonikidze) (Reel 127)
  - Soviet Courts (Reel 128)
  - Krakow (Poland) Remembers Lenin (Reel 129)
  - With Love in Our Hearts: The Music Lenin Loved (Reel 130)
  - To the Tip of the Planet (Reel 131)
  - Colors of Turkmenia (Reel 132)
  - The Right to Housing (Reel 133)
  - Motherhood (Reel 134)
  - The Way to the Skies (training pilots) (Reel 135)
  - Council for Economic Assistance: Part I (Reel 136)
  - Council for Economic Assistance: Part II (Reel 137)
  - 7th World Congress of Twin Towns (Reel 138)
  - Kirghiz SSR (Reel 139)
  - U.S. Young Farm Group Visits USSR (Reel 140)
  - Around the Soviet Union: Sochi, Tbilisi (Reel 141)
  - Envoys of Peace and Friendship (Reel 142)
  - Hammer and Sickle Places of Culture (Reel 143)
  - Spreading Soviet Culture (Reel 144)
  - A Pioneer Palace (Reel 145)
  - Our Youth (Reel 146)
  - On Guard for Health (Reel 147)
  - Dedicated to 60th Anniversary (Reel 148)
  - Senior Citizens of Central Asia (Reel 149)
  - Under the Banner of the 60th Anniversary (Reel 150)
  - Belorussian SSR (Reel 151)
  - The Leninist Peace Policy (Reel 152)
  - Soviet-Chinese Friendship Society (Reel 153)
  - The Moscow Virtuoso (Reel 154)
  - Sheepbreeding (Reel 155)
  - Dushambe, Capital of Tadzhikistan (Reel 156)
  - Brezhnev: Pages from His Life (Reel 157)
  - Leningrad (Reel 158)
  - Leningrad and Lenin's Birthday (Reel 159)
  - Seminar in Minsk (Reel 160)
  - Soviet Social Security (Reel 161)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 162)
  - Three Portraits (Reel 163)
  - Peace through Humanism: Socialist Red Cross (Reel 164)
  - The Sound of the Bugle: ARTEK (Reel 165)
  - To Live in the Twenty-first Century (Reel 166)
  - The Pioneer Summer Camp (Reel 167)
  - Centuries within 60 Years (Reel 168)
  - The Village of Bergiliskii (Reel 169)
  - Odessa and Varna (Reel 170)
  - Amateur Talent (Reel 171)
  - Animals in Siberia (Reel 172)
  - The Moscow Ballbearing Plant (Reel 173)
  - Kishinev, Capital of the Moldavian SSR (Reel 174)
  - Story of a Communist: Brezhnev (Reel 175)
  - From Air to Ground: Parachute Training (Reel 176)
  - Friendship with the Peoples of Africa (Reel 177)
  - A Lesson in Peace (Reel 178)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 179)
  - The Water of Life (Lithuanian SSR) (Reel 180)
  - For Your Children (festival of children's talent) (Reel 181)
  - At the 26th Congress of the CPSU (Reel 182)
  - The Truth of the Newspaper Pravda (Reel 183)
  - Let's Get Acquainted: Part I (Reel 184)
  - Let's Get Acquainted: Part II (Reel 185)
  - Soldiers of the Liberation Army (Reel 186)
  - Tbilisi, Georgian SSR (Reel 187)
  - Lenin in Emigration (Reel 188)
  - Young Mechanics (Reel 189)
  - Our Youth (Reel 190)
  - The Moscow Kremlin (Reel 191)
  - Land of Our Birth: Past and Present Jewish Life in the USSR (Reel 192)
  - A Little Girl and Her Place in the Summer Camp (Reel 193)
  - Around the Soviet Union: Lake Baikal, Siberia (Reel 194)
  - Tales of Siberia (Reel 195)
  - Military Strategic Parity (Reel 196)
  - Russian Winter Festival of Arts (Reel 197)
  - The New Heights: 26th Congress of the CPSU (Reel 198)
  - Classmates (Reel 199)
  - Home for Theater Veterans (Reel 200)
  - Lenin: First Years of the Revolution (Reel 201)
  - Belorussia in Colors (Reel 202)
  - Preparing for 27th Congress, CPSU (Reel 203)
  - The Right to Rest, Leisure and Health Protection (Reel 204)
  - The Right to Work (Reel 205)
  - "With Leninism in My Heart": Reminiscences by a Co-worker (Reel 206)
  - My Lithuania (Reel 207)
  - State Concern for the Children (Reel 208)
  - Starting Out in Life: From Birth through Grade School (Reel 209)
  - Our Student Years Have Made Us Friends (Reel 210)
  - National Sports of the Soviet People (Reel 211)
  - Turkmenian SSR Culture: Rug-making (Reel 212)
  - Siberia Invites You (Reel 213)
  - Color and Rhythm: Turkmenia (Reel 214)
  - One Day at a Movie Studio (Moscow) (Reel 215)
  - About Soviet Sciences (Reel 216)
  - Geneva: Start of a Dialogue (Reel 217)
  - Children's Railroad (Reel 218)
  - Dockers (Reel 219)
  - Environmental Protection (Reel 220)
  - Freedom of Conscience (Reel 221)
  - I Want to Be a Worker (Reel 222)
  - Unesco International Conference on Books, Moscow (Reel 223)
  - Rebuilding Tashkent: Quake, 1966 (Reel 224)
  - Abreast of the Time (Reel 225)
  - Leningrad Plant (in Spanish) (Reel 226)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 227)
  - Dance Natasha (Reel 228)
  - Kiev: What a City (Reel 229)
  - Invitation to the Olympics, 1980 (Reel 230)
  - Festival of Friendship (Reel 231)
  - Women of Uzbekistan (Reel 232)
  - Along Red Square (Reel 233)
  - The Population of the USSR (Reel 234)
  - Georgian Children (Reel 235)
  - Soviet Health and Medical Plans (Reel 236)
  - Ballet School (Reel 237)
  - Soviet Armenia (Reel 238)
  - An Unusual Theater: Animals for Children (Reel 239)
  - Jewelry by Soviet Artisans (Reel 240)
  - Spanish (Reel 241)
  - Soviet Navy in the Mediterranean (Reel 242)
  - The Doctors of Kalinovka (Reel 243)
  - They Are Building Moscow (Reel 244)
  - Architectural Discoveries in the Ukraine (Reel 245)
  - Sight in Birds (Reel 246)
  - Riga, Capital of Soviet Latvia (Reel 247)
  - Soviet Latvia (Reel 248)
  - Sports Rhythms (Reel 249)
  - The Builders (Reel 250)
  - National Folk Art (Reel 251)
  - Water Colors (Reel 252)
  - Secrets of the Moscow Circus (Reel 253)
  - No to the Atom Bomb (Reel 254)
  - Dancing School: Ballet (Reel 255)
  - Pinyonkov: A Talent of Russia: Sculpture (Reel 256)
  - Tallinn (Reel 257)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 258)
  - Siberia Invites You (Reel 259)
  - A Song about Seven Daughters (teachers) (Reel 260)
  - Super Cup: Kiev Soccer (Reel 261)
  - Rehabilitation for Blind People (Reel 262)
  - The Moscow Kremlin (Reel 263)
  - Belovezh Preserve in Ukraine (Reel 264)
  - The Silver Sound of the Brass Band (Reel 265)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 266)
  - Masters of Sports (Reel 267)
  - The Electrification of the USSR (Reel 268)
  - By the Deep Blue Sea (Reel 269)
  - Tadzhikistan Melodies (Reel 270)
  - Vilnius as It Looks Today (Reel 271)
  - Kishinev, Capital of Moldavia (Reel 272)
  - Four Soviet War Heroes Meet in Volgograd (Reel 273)
  - The Miracle Frost (cartoon) (Reel 274)
  - The Golden Ring (Reel 275)
  - The Wolf and the Tailor (cartoon) (Reel 276)
  - Let's Dance the Charkhuduzonu (Reel 277)
  - Soviet Ukraine (Reel 278)
  - Tales from Sakhalin Island (Reel 279)
  - Meet Alexander Pushkin (Reel 280)
  - Our Golden Childhood (Reel 281)
  - Making Things Better for Man (Reel 282)
  - The Belaya River (Reel 283)
  - Amateur Talent (Reel 284)
  - Soviet Sports: Asian Republics (Reel 285)
  - A Loaf of Bread: Russian Holiday (Reel 286)
  - Minsk, Belorussia (Reel 287)
  - The Soviet Banking System from, 1917 (Reel 288)
  - Moscow under Construction (Reel 289)
  - Moscow Transportation (Reel 290)
  - Antarctica: The White Magnet (Reel 291)
  - In the Far East (Reel 292)
  - Around the Soviet Union: Animal Farm (Reel 293)
  - Science in Siberia: Building of Sciencetown (Reel 294)
  - Friendship Congress in Moscow (Reel 295)
  - The Legion that Began (Spain) (Reel 296)
  - Tales of Siberia (Reel 297)
  - Black American Delegation (Reel 298)
  - Ring of Friendship (Reel 299)
  - From Saturday to Monday (Reel 300)
  - The Land of Young Masters (Reel 301)
  - Across Siberia to Lake Baikal (Reel 302)
  - The Sculptor (Reel 303)
  - The State Structure of the USSR (Reel 304)
  - Zagorsk (Reel 305)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 306)
  - Architecture in Moscow (Reel 307)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 308)
  - Winter in Siberia (Reel 309)
  - If I Were a Magician (cartoon) (Reel 310)
  - Songs of Svanetiya (Reel 311)
  - My Poltava (Reel 312)
  - Kazan (Reel 313)
  - Council for Mutual Economic Assistance 30th Anniversary (Reel 314)
  - Lenin in Switzerland (Reel 315)
  - Dedicated to Ballet (Reel 316)
  - Student Years (Reel 317)
  - Folkcrafts (Reel 318)
  - A Pioneer Palace (Reel 319)
  - An American Farmer Visits the USSR (Reel 320)
  - The Neutron Bomb (Reel 321)
  - Around the Halls of a Russian Museum (Reel 322)
  - The Treasures of the Russian Museum (Reel 323)
  - Treasures of the Russian Museum, Leningrad (Reel 324)
  - How Animals See (Reel 325)
  - The Earth Is Our Home (Reel 326)
  - Sports for One and All (Reel 327)
  - Not on Any Map: New Cities Created in Central Asia (Reel 328)
  - Kazakhstan Melodies (Reel 329)
  - Story of a Communist: Brezhnev: Reel 1 (Reel 330)
  - Story of a Communist: Brezhnev: Reel 2 (Reel 331)
  - Soviet Far East (Reel 332)
  - The Land I Love: 50th Anniversary Accomplishments: Reel 1 (Reel 333)
  - The Land I Love: 50th Anniversary Accomplishments: Reel 2 (Reel 334)
  - Lenin Dream in Action (Reel 335)
  - The Art of Russian Jewelry (Tsarist crown, etc.) (Reel 336)
  - Twenty-seven Minutes about Russia (Reel 337)
  - The Great Exploit: Reel 1 (Reel 338)
  - The Great Exploit: Reel 2 (Reel 339)
  - The Dawning of Buryatia (Reel 340)
  - Welcome to USSR Friendship House, Moscow (Reel 341)
  - Our Leningrad: Reel 1 (Reel 342)
  - Our Leningrad: Reel 2 (Reel 343)
  - The Fifteen Soviet Republics: Reel 1 (Reel 344)
  - The Fifteen Soviet Republics: Reel 2 (Reel 345)
  - Unusual Days of Great History (Reel 346)
  - Unbreakable Union (Reel 347)
  - Moscow Conservatory (Reel 348)
  - Life of Fedor Dostoevsky (Reel 349)
  - Space Stations, Reel 2, 1957-1976: (Reel 350)
  - The Land of Our Birth: Jewish Life in the USSR: Reel 2 (Reel 351)
  - Meridians of Friendship: Cultural Exchange: Reel 2 (Reel 352)
  - The Amber Baltic Coast: Reel 2 (Reel 353)
  - Lenin in October: Reel 1 (Reel 354)
  - October Days: Reel 1 (Reel 355)
  - October Days: Reel 2 (Reel 356)
  - The Grass Grows Red Here: Africa (Reel 357)
  - Danger from Maoism (Reel 358)
  - Soviet Theater Today (Reel 359)
  - In Commemoration of Shostakovich (Reel 360)
  - Fourth Tchaikovsky Competition (Reel 361)
  - Around the Soviet Union (Reel 362)
  - A Tadzhik: Ancient Cultures and Customs (Reel 363)
  - Siberian Forest School (Reel 364)
  - October 1917: Reel 2 (Reel 365)
  - The Circus Comes to Town (Reel 366)
- Rest of collection not yet described